Attack Force Z is a war, action film directed by Tim Burstall.
Sent to rescue survivors from the site of a plane crash in the South Pacific during WWII, Captain Kelly and his elite squad
of Australian commandos must keep tabs on a defecting Japanese official who could hold the secret to peace.
Captain Kelly, played by Mel Gibson.
Lieutenant Veitch, played by John Phillip Law.
Sergeant Costello, played by Sam Neill.
Able Seaman A.D. 'Sparrer' Bird, played by Chris Haywood.
Chien Hua, played by Sylvia Chang.
Lin Chan-Lang, played by Ko Chun-Hsiung.
Attack Force Z (alternatively titled The Z Men) is a 1982 war film directed by Tim Burstall,
and starring John Phillip Law, Mel Gibson, Sam Neill, and Koo Chuan Hsiung.
It dramatizes the exploits of Z Special Unit, also known as Z Force, a
joint Australian, British and New Zealand commando unit.
Its main brief was to conduct reconnaissance and sabotage missions throughout
Imperial Japanese-occupied Southeast Asia during the Second World War.
The film is noted for starring Mel Gibson and Sam Neill, who were relatively unknown
in the US at the time but who went on to become international stars.
It was an international co-production between Australia and
Taiwan, and was filmed on-location in Taiwan.
It was screened at the Cannes Film Festival on 18 May 1981.
The film explores themes of mission, submarine,
world war ii, airplane crash, commando.